mytechguide.org 2017-11-20

# My Technology Guide Privacy Policy

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookie, Usage data, Email address, First Name, Last Name, Username and Various types of Data.

Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection. The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application.

Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User. Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services.

Users are responsible for any Personal Data of third parties obtained, published or shared through this Application and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.

The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.  
Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.  
Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

### The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Contacting the User, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Registration and authentication, Access to third party services’ accounts, Handling payments, Interaction with support and feedback platforms, Infrastructure monitoring, Traffic optimization and distribution, Interaction with live chat platforms, Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting, Managing contacts and sending messages, Displaying content from external platforms, Commercial affiliation, Heat mapping, User database management and Managing support and contact requests.

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

### Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

These services allow User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on this Application, possibly based on User interests. This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below. Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside this Application. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.

### Advertisements

#### BuySellAds (BuySellAds.com Inc.)

BuySellAds is an advertising service provided by BuySellAds.com Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://buysellads.com/about/privacy)

#### IDG TechNetwork (IDG TechNetwork, Inc.)

IDG TechNetwork is an advertising service provided by IDG TechNetwork, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://idgtechnetwork.com/terms/)

#### Google AdSense (Google Inc.)

Google AdSense is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks use of this Application and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.

Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on:

google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

#### VigLink (VigLink, Inc.)

VigLink is a commercial affiliation service provided by VigLink, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.viglink.com/legal/) – [Opt Out](http://www.viglink.com/opt-out/)

### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Analytics collected directly (This Application)

This Application uses an internal analytics system that does not involve third parties.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

#### Display Advertising extension for Google Analytics (Google)

Google Analytics on this Application might use Google’s Interest-based advertising, 3rd-party audience data and information from the DoubleClick Cookie to extend analytics with demographics, interests and ads interaction data.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

#### Google Analytics with anonymized IP (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
This integration of Google Analytics anonymizes your IP address. It works by shortening Users’ IP addresses within Member States of the European Union or in other Contracting States to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be sent to a Google server and shortened within the USA.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

#### MixPanel (MixPanel)

MixPanel is an analytics service provided by Mixpanel Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://mixpanel.com/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://mixpanel.com/optout/)

#### WordPress Stats (Automattic Inc.)

WordPress Stats is an analytics service provided by Automattic Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing: USA

### Contacting the User

#### Mailing List or Newsletter (This Application)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning this Application. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to this Application or after making a purchase.

Personal Data collected: Email address, First Name and Last Name (Optional).

#### Contact form (This Application)

By filling in the contact form with their Data, the User authorizes this Application to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.

Personal Data collected: Email address, First Name, Last Name and Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

### Content commenting

Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of this Application.

#### Comment system managed directly (This Application)

This Application has its own internal content comment system.

Personal Data collected: Cookie, Email address, First Name, Last Name,

Usage data and Username.

### Hosting and backend infrastructure

These services have the purpose of hosting data and files that enable this Application to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of this Application. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

### Infrastructure monitoring

These services allow this Application to monitor the use and behavior of its components so its performance, operation, maintenance and troubleshooting can be improved. Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these services, whose function is to filter the activities of this Application.

#### Pingdom (Pingdom AB)

Pingdom is a monitoring service provided by Pingdom AB.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.

Place of processing: Sweden – [Privacy Policy](https://www.pingdom.com/legal/privacy-policy)

### How can I manage the installation of Cookies?

In addition to what is specified in this document, the User can manage preferences for Cookies directly from within their own browser and prevent – for example – third parties from installing them. Through the browser preferences, it is also possible to delete Cookies installed in the past, including the Cookies that might possibly have saved the consent for the installation of Cookies by this website. It is important to note that by disabling all Cookies, the functioning of this site may be compromised. Users can find information about how to manage Cookies in their browser at the following addresses: [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&p=cpn_cookies), [Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences), [Apple Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH19214?viewlocale=en_US&locale=en_US) and [Microsoft Windows Explorer](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-vista/block-or-allow-cookies).

In the case of services provided by third parties, Users can exercise their right to withdraw from the tracking activity by utilizing the information provided in the third party’s privacy policy, by clicking the opt-out link – if provided – or by contacting the third party.

Notwithstanding the above, the Owner informs that Users may take advantage of: [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). This service allows Users to select their tracking preferences for most of the advertising tools. The Owner thus recommends that Users make use of this resource in addition to the information provided in this document.
